Kenneth Llerena

kenneth.llerena@outlook.com | linkedin.com/in/kennethllerena | (305) 903 - 5614 | Raleigh, NC

Professional Summary

Disciplined leader with 3 years of U.S. Army experience, transitioning into an IT support role. Possess a diverse background in data analytics, communications, and intelligence reporting, providing a unique technical knowledge base. Seeking to leverage interpersonal skills honed through military service to contribute effectively to an IT department. Eager to apply a solutions-oriented mindset and adaptability to troubleshoot user issues and provide excellent customer service.

Certifications and Skills

• Certifications: Google IT Support Professional

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Linux, Bash, Microsoft Active Directory, and Microsoft 365

Clearance: Secret ClearanceLanguage: Spanish - Fluent

Experience

Infantryman, U.S. Army - Fort Liberty, NC

Apr 2021- Present

- Compiled and formatted reports from various software packages to develop plans, which helped establish 10% more beneficial technologies.
- Researched data analytics from diverse radio systems and reports to deliver mission-critical intelligence, enabling secure communications and decisive operations for 651 personnel.
- Tested communication software to ensure quality assurance to decrease systems being inoperative saving my team \$5773.
- Cultivated cultural awareness and interpersonal skills by collaborating with diverse teams, enabling effective information sharing and achieving organizational goals.

IT Support Technician, CardConnect – Raleigh, NC (Hybrid)

Jun 2019 - Apr 2021

- Provided IT support to customers, resolving issues with their Point-of-Sale (POS) systems and ensuring uninterrupted business operations.
- Leveraged POS programming expertise to assist customers with First Data and Clover POS systems through on-site support and utilizing the Clover Customer Relationship Management (CRM), reducing support tickets by 19%.
- Streamlined inventory provisioning by using Microsoft Excel to create easily adjustable templates, allowing customers to receive POS systems with their inventory pre-populated.
- Configured basic LAN setups, including routers, printers, and computers, to support small businesses.

Assistant Site Manager, Providence Construction – Clayton, NC

Mar 2020 - Apr 2021

- Led a team of 5 individuals that enabled completion of Thanksgiving Elementary School and 44 new homes.
- Optimized payroll management and workforce planning to ensure on-time, \$13.97M project completion through accurate employee compensation, data-driven scheduling decisions, and efficient resource allocation.
- Maintained detailed documentation and inventory of all construction site-related hardware, verifying tasks were completed and adjusted accordingly.

Education

Liberty University

Bachelors of Science (B.S.) - Computer Science